<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cultivate</title>
    <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cultivate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cultivateoakland.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunter&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/hunter/</guid>
      <description>Hunter is a junior at Oakland University studying pre-physical therapy. Hunter joined Cultivate’s process in the spring of 2019 and has grown tremendously in his faith and as a leader since joining. When Hunter began the Cultivate process, he thought that he was “close” to God, but what unaware of the intimacy that could have with the Father.
As a freshman Hunter spottily attended Younglife, a campus ministry at Oakland University designed to help people experience the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/rachel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/rachel/</guid>
      <description>Rachel is a senior at Oakland University studying pre-physical therapy. She joined the Cultivate process in the spring of 2016, and since has grown tremendously in her faith. When Rachel began the Cultivate process her faith was young and not her own, but the product of the way she was raised. Rachel had a strong desire to grow in her relationship with God, but lacked the tools and guidance needed to become an effective kingdom worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blake and Tina</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/blake-and-tina/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/blake-and-tina/</guid>
      <description>Blake Pokley is a senior at Oakland University. This is a story he wrote to inspire others to help someone he found in need. This story is a beautiful example of seeing people through the eyes of Christ, and the power of deep friendships between kingdom workers like Blake, Phill, and Kyle.
On my way to work Wednesday, I was on Baldwin Road in Lake Orion and traffic was backed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justin&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/justin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/justin/</guid>
      <description>Justin arrived at Oakland from Beijing in the fall of 2014 as a Master’s student in Computer Science. Like many international students, he did not have friends, family, or familiar faces greeting him as he arrived. He knew a place where he could live with a roommate, but beyond that, he did not have anything more than the clothes in his suitcase.
This same fall semester that Justin arrived, Cultivate was working to find ways to serve incoming international students at Oakland University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyle&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/kyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/kyle/</guid>
      <description>Kyle came to Oakland as a transfer student in fall of 2016, following two years of college athletics at a Christian college. Kyle knew a handful of Christian friends at Oakland, but didn’t have a direction for his faith in relation to his campus. He was drawn to Cultivate’s desire to develop kingdom workers, and he entered the Cultivate process about 3 week into his first semester at Oakland.
As part of his first semester within Cultivate, Kyle joined a men’s group, went to a weekly class designed to deepen his understanding of faith topics, met one on one with a mentor, and surveyed the opportunities available through campus organizations and ministries that would help grow God’s Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David-Chad&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/dc/</guid>
      <description>Identity Formation (Before High School): DC grew up in a suburban, white, Catholic family. But, it was clear that church was about religion and not relationship and his parents divorced when he was 7. He was the third of three siblings and his relationship with his old brother grew increasingly hostile after the divorce. Though he knew his parents loved him and both remained present in his life, his father often seemed to put work first and wasn’t always able to his kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Told by Cam Underdown, Cultivate Founder In 2012, I felt the call to come back to Oakland University to pastor the people of the campus. God gave me three specific directives in leaving the ministry I had at Kensington, and beginning the new one at Oakland:
 Find, gather, and strengthen believers Serve existing campus ministries and organizations Don’t recruit a team, but let God send the initial workers  These three directions were difficult for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Kingdom Worker</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/students/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for people who are faithful, available, and teachable to join our network and grow in their character, understanding, and leadership. In order to best do this, we suggest:
 Meeting weekly with a mentor (we can help connect you with a mentor) Attending a weekly class (such as spiritual gifts, apologetics, or biblical interpretation) Serving within an existing campus ministry or campus organization (with the hope of welcoming people to follow Jesus) Attending occasional trainings on personality type, leadership styles, and other assessment tools  We recognize it’s a large commitment, but over the last 5 years, we have seen those who want to see God’s Kingdom grow become well equipped to do so through this commitment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultivate Kingdom Worker Development Fund</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/donate/kwdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/donate/kwdf/</guid>
      <description>Cultivate’s mission is to develop kingdom workers, and we find the best way to do this is to help give young men and women opportunities where they can serve others in hands-on, practical ways while being coached in meaningful ways by loving leaders. For example, a senior engineering student wants to lead a team which deliberately focuses on students who would never come to church or a campus ministry. He wants to run the Alpha course because he knows it has structure and proven success at welcoming people who wouldn’t normally come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/strategy/</guid>
      <description>We look for people who desire to grow God’s Kingdom, and serve them in any way we can. Maybe it’s starting a brand new endeavor with a visionary college student to meet an injustice. Maybe it’s partnering with an existing ministry to build a new team that will help that ministry meet its next God-given goal. Maybe it’s working through a difficult addiction or past issue with a Christian student to get that person ready for kingdom service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kelly&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/kelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/kelly/</guid>
      <description>Kelly started with Cultivate in its first semester in 2013 as a freshman at Oakland. Coming from a missionary family, Kelly knew a lot about her faith, the bible, and the importance of reaching out. However, even with an incredible family, she still had her obstacles to overcome.
A fear of missing out on God’s promptings for her life was one such obstacle. As a successful student-athlete in high school, Kelly had a plan and direction for her life, but she was afraid of one day waking up and thinking she had missed or left God’s plan some place in the distant past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brian&#39;s Story</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/brian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/stories/brian/</guid>
      <description>Brian became involved with Cultivate in February 2016 after being recommended by a local church to connect with Cultivate leaders at Oakland. This was one of his first times coming back to a church since he began college in 2014, and he didn’t exactly know what to expect from a meeting with ministry leaders, especially at Oakland, where he was extremely well-known and involved.
Brian had grown up as a Christian, going to church with his mom nearby his home in westside Detroit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/dc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/donate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/rsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/rsa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/sldf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/sldf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service1/</guid>
      <description>We believe that God works through individuals and teams to accomplish his purposes in the world - who we call kingdom workers. These people need well-established Christlike character to effectively love the people who they are called to love by God and advance his Kingdom in their lives. Through prayer, education, mentoring, and hands-on training, we at Cultivate develop people to grow God’s Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service2/</guid>
      <description>We believe our God is a God of specifics. He has a plan in mind for every person, creating everyone with particular work to do. In addition, God has specific ways He wants things done – there are essential qualities of justice, kindness, and excellence that go into every one of his plans. When someone listens for and clearly discerns the specific plan God gives, God’s Kingdom grows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer</title>
      <link>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cultivateoakland.org/service/service3/</guid>
      <description>Prayer often is the critical element of success in growing God’s Kingdom. No matter how gifted a person or team is, no matter how solid a plan is, success and failure rests on God’s favor. Our hope is to equip people and teams with initial groups who can petition God for guidance and success in their plans, as well as spiritually “cover” each individual who is working to grow God’s Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>